# **Vladimir Ternovykh**

Redwood City, CA

vlterno@gmail.com

+1 (857) 347-6788

Portfolio vlterno.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Mechanical design engineer with a passion for human-centered design as well as the development of new products, especially for startups. In my portfolio: launched <u>Formlabs Quick Release Build Platform</u>, IF DESIGN AWARD 2021 for the handheld 3D Scanner "Calibry" of my engineering design. 7 years of experience in product development from the blueprint of an idea to production. Skilled in CAD, manufacturing, injection molding, prototyping, design for manufacturing, quality control and inspection.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Mechanical Engineer**

Apr 2022 - Sep 2023

Formlabs Inc

Formlabs HQ, Sommerville, MA

- Launched the Quick Release Build Platforms (from scratch to MP)
- Worked on the high cosmetic parts of the new generation of the Formlabs 3D printer
- Developed accessories for the Fuse (Formlabs SLS printer) Responsibilities:
  - Leading independent projects that span both mechanical and industrial design sides
  - Creating detailed designs in CAD and drawings (OnShape). PLM/document control systems (Propel)
  - Collaborating with Global Sourcing, Manufacturing, and Testing teams
  - Product risk assessment, product validation planning and testing. Creating fixtures and jigs
  - Quality control and inspection (IQC, IPQC, FQC), inspection criteria. Troubleshooting mass production
  - Prototyping new mechanisms, testing materials, and research 3D printing challenges

### Lead Design Engineer ART UP Studio LLC

Aug 2017 - Jan 2022

Moscow, Skolkovo Innovation Center, Russia

- More than 50 projects successfully taken from concept to prototype or mass product.
- Mechanical and design engineering (CAD, CAE, CAM), design and engineering research
- Project management, team-leading, engineering support of industrial design team, collaborating with electrical engineers. Estimating resource requirements, monitoring progress and balancing as needed. Direct communication with a client and top management
- Accomplishments: the international iF Product Design Award 2021 for the handheld 3D Scanner "Calibry" of
  my engineering (it is already on the market), "XENONIUM" therapeutic device for the inhalation of medical
  xenon of my mechanical engineering is nominated for the iF Design Award 2022, utility patent RU #127951 of
  the Power Lines Monitoring Sensor, 3D Feet Scanner "TRYFIT" of my design passed to the final selection in
  the iF Design Award 2021

#### **Mechanical Engineer**

Jun 2018 - Feb 2020

**MAJI LLC** 

Moscow, Skolkovo Innovation Center, Russia

 Development of SMART PACK device for individual filtration, processing and purification of liquid products based on nano-sorbents

### Design Engineer Objectlab LLC

Dec 2016 - Apr 2017

Moscow, Russia

- Mechanical engineering (CAD), 3D rendering. Designing a smart parking sensor for mass production.
- European Product Design Award for the external battery charger "One", my contribution was in the visualization of the device.

# **Junior Engineer**

Jun 2015 – Jun 2016

Telum LLC (Ranberry)

Skolkovo Innovation Center, Russia

Developing the first LTE base station in Russia: CAD, assembly, and testing of prototypes, 3D visualization

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree in engineering,

2011 - 2016

Bauman Moscow State Technical University Materials and Technology Department

# SKILLS

CAD (CATIA, Onshape, Fusion 360, SolidWorks), engineering reports (DFM, BOM), manufacturing (injection molding, CNC, sheet metal), additive technologies (FDM, SLA, SLS), engineering drawings (tolerancing), simulation (Fusion 360, Ansys), reverse engineering (3D scanning, STL-reconstruction), renderings & graphics (Keyshot, Illustrator)